{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which is the most common carbon source used in the plant cell culture media?", "opta": "Sucrose", "optb": "Glucose", "optc": "Fructose", "optd": "Maltose", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an ethylene biosynthesis inhibitor?", "opta": "Citric acid", "optb": "Succinic acid", "optc": "Activated charcoal", "optd": "Silver thiosulphate", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nitrogen in the plant cell culture media is provided by either ammonia or nitrate salt. In the media", "opta": "utilization of ammonium cause culture pH to drop while utilization of nitrate cause culture pH to rise", "optb": "utilization of nitrate cause culture pH to drop while utilization of ammonium cause culture pH to rise", "optc": "utilization of both ammonium and nitrate result in rise in pH", "optd": "utilization of both ammonium and nitrate result in drop in pH", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following growth regulator is added for short initiation during plant regeneration from callus?", "opta": "Auxins", "optb": "Cytokinins", "optc": "Gibberellins", "optd": "Brassinosteroids", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following growth regulator promote cell division?", "opta": "Auxins", "optb": "Cytokinins", "optc": "Gibberellins", "optd": "Brassinosteroids", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following growth regulator is used to stimulate embryo or shoot development?", "opta": "Auxins", "optb": "Cytokinins", "optc": "Gibberellins", "optd": "Brassinosteroids", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following growth regulator cause plant cells to grow?", "opta": "Auxins", "optb": "Cytokinins", "optc": "Gibberellins", "optd": "Brassinosteroids", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Silver thiosulphate is added to culture medium as it helps to", "opta": "maintain the pH", "optb": "remove toxic phenolics from plant cells", "optc": "prevent the gaseous plant hormone, ethylene dioxide from accumulating to detrimental condition.", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In plant cell culture media, auxins and cytokinins are used in the range of", "opta": "l-50\u03bcM", "optb": "50-100\u03bcM", "optc": "100-125\u03bcM", "optd": "more than 125\u03bcM", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Concentration of sucrose generally used in plant cell culture media is", "opta": "10-15 g/l", "optb": "20-30 g/l", "optc": "40-50 g/l", "optd": "60-70 g/l", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is/are the naturally occurring plant auxins?", "opta": "Indole acetic acid (IAA)", "optb": "Naphthalenacetic acid (NAA)", "optc": "2,4-dichlorophenoxyacetic acid", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is/are the disadvantage/(s) of using IAA in plant cell culture media?", "opta": "It is unstable in solution", "optb": "Gets easily oxidized", "optc": "Conjugated to inactive form by plant cells", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To maintain the pH of the culture", "opta": "organic acid such as citric, fumaric, malic and succinic acid is used", "optb": "synthetic buffers such as Tris, MES or HEPS are used", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "ammonium salts are used", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a cytokinin?", "opta": "2,4-dichlorophenoxyacetic acid", "optb": "6 benzylaminopurine", "optc": "Zeatin", "optd": "Kinetin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an auxin?", "opta": "Indole acetic acid (IAA)", "optb": "Naphthalenacetic acid (NAA)", "optc": "zeatin", "optd": "Indole butyric acid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true about nurse or conditioned medium?", "opta": "It is liquid removed from the suspension of fast growing cells", "optb": "It contains uncharacterized growth factor released by growing cells", "optc": "It is used in the culture of regenerating protoplast", "optd": "it is removed aseptically from the culture and is autoclaved before use", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Very high sugar concentration (40-100 g/l) have been used", "opta": "in specialized secondary metabolite production", "optb": "to adjust the osmotic potential of the media in short term treatment for regeneration", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is 'nurse' or conditioned medium?", "opta": "It is the media full of growth factors used for the growth of cells", "optb": "It is the medium added to nurse the callus culture", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "It is the liquid medium removed from the suspension of fast growing cells", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the macronutrients used in plant cell culture medium?", "opta": "N, P, K, S, Na", "optb": "N, P, K, Ca, Cl", "optc": "N, P, K, S, Ca", "optd": "N, P, Ca, Na, Cl", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Neutralized activated charcoal is occasionally added to young regenerating cultures to", "opta": "remove toxic phenolics produced by the stressed plant cell", "optb": "help to remove plants growth regulators introduced at an earlier stage", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "maintain the pH of the medium", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}